# **NICHOLAS SEIDL**

# Machine Learning Engineer

I have experience working on various **computer vision, natural language processing,** and **machine learning** projects. I'm currently at Apple in Intelligent System Experience - System Intelligence Machine Learning working on Generative AI. I built a **real-time object detector (YOLO)** for Wayfair in Summer 2019. In Spring 2019, I worked on **robustness analysis** (RA) of Apple's Neural Face Detector. In Spring + Summer 2018, I built two **web services** at Apple: one for **content analysis and retrieval** and one for **hosted image comparisons and history**.

#### **Contact**

nicholasseidl@gmail.com (650)-739-6674



nseidl.io



/in/nicholaskseidl



github.com/nseidl

## Languages

Python, Java, Javascript, C, C++

## **Software**

GenAl, LLMs, VQA, RLHF, CLIP, PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras, Pandas, NumPy, CoreML, TensorRT, TFLite, Flask, React, Postgres, AWS, EC2, S3, Docker, Airflow, Kubernetes

#### Courses

Algorithms and Data Structures Artificial Intelligence Linear Algebra Distributed Systems ML and Data Mining Object Oriented Design Computer Systems Programming Languages Probability and Statistics

#### **Interests**

Formula 1, Chess, Pool, Photography, Basketball, Hiking

# **Experience**

Apple Inc.

Cupertino, CA February 2020 - Present

ISE SIML - Machine Learning Engineer

- Data science, mining, and pipelining for multi-modal (<image/video>+text) models (like <u>CLIP</u>, <u>GPT</u>, <u>Diffusion</u>, <u>GSAM</u>, <u>BLIP</u>, etc.) using novel curation techniques (transformers, clustering, foundation models, zeroshot classfiers)
  - Curate the "best assets" subset from a larger dataset (Semantic DeDupe)
- Rapid creation of image classifiers using Zero-Shot CLIP techniques
- Designed and implemented robust and scalable data pipeline for validation, ingestion, and publication of data for ML (100TB+, 100M+ assets, monthly)
- NLP pipelining for evolving corpora: 500B+ words; 50+ languages
- Programmatically provide insights for arbitrary data
  - Clustering, bias and outlier detection, distribution tests
- Robustness analysis and data pipelining for Visual Lookup (<u>WWDC '21</u>)

Wayfair LLC

Boston, MA

Data Science - Computer Vision Engineer

June 2019 - Aug. 2019

- Implemented YOLO(v3) neural network for live on-device object detection
- Optimized with quantization, CUDA, cuDNN, TensorRT, and Tensor Cores
- Achieved 80x speedup in inference time and up to 4x smaller model sizes

Apple Inc.

Cupertino, CA

C&P CVML - Machine Learning Engineer

Jan. 2019 - June 2019

- Analyzed failures of face detector to target aggressors and guide development
- Designed and automated RA pipeline: inference → detection evaluation → RA
- Managed data collection, selection, and annotation (guidelines, spec, and quality)

Apple Inc.

Cupertino, CA

IMG QE - Full Stack Software Engineer

Jan. 2018 - Aug. 2018

- Content Collection: audio/image/video/stream analysis and retrieval (Tornado)
  - Integrated blob (Amazon S3) and metadata (Postgres) stores to serve content
  - Extracted attributes from audio, image, video, and stream content (Swift)
- Image Comparisons: image comparison web service with history (Flask)
  - Rewrote backend so different comparison algorithms can easily be added

#### **Education**

Northeastern University

Boston, MA

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science
Khoury College of Computer Sciences

GPA: 3.6 / 4.0

Sep. 2015 - Dec. 2019